Deep inside the forbidden area
禁域的深处
is the Grave, where those who had supernatural abilities are buried.
是神墓 那里埋葬着异能者
That is the place where
那里是
spirits that turned into Grotesqueries because of negative sentiments
死后因负面情绪而化身成异形的怨灵
are meant to be sealed off permanently.
被永久封印的地方
If it is true that the Grave was opened
如果神墓真的被打开
and the Grotesqueries were awakened...
异形们被唤醒了
The imperial city will face an unparalleled crisis.
那么帝都将会面临前所未有的危机
It would not be an exaggeration to say so.
这绝不是夸大其词
Who was it that broke the seal, and for what purpose?
到底是谁因何目的解开了封印?
Prince Takaihito received a revelation at around the same time.
与此同时 尭人大人收到天启
It couldn't be a coincidence.
这绝非偶然
Although, he has said his powers are still unstable
不过我说自己因尚未承袭帝位
because he hasn't succeeded to the throne yet...
因此力量尚不稳定
Nevertheless, we are not in a position to speculate.
以我等水平 无法随意揣测
Ah. It's been a while, Mr. Kudo.
好久不见 久堂先生
Mr. Okaito.
大海渡先生
Hey, Tatsuishi.
辰石 你这个人
Are you going to meet the prince looking like that?
你打算这身打扮觐见吗?
I thought there weren't any rules I have to follow
除了听命帝上
besides obeying the Mikado.
并无其他繁杂规矩
Can't you show a modicum of common courtesy?
最低限度的礼数总要做好吧?
This is my formal attire.
这就是我的正装
I wish you wouldn't be so uptight.
你不要这么死板
This time only. I won't let you off the hook next time.
只有这次 下不为例
Come now. You should relax more.
好了 不要这么剑拔弩张
Excuse me.
容我等
It's Okaito, Kudo, and Tatsuishi. We have arrived.
大海渡、久堂、辰石参拜大人
Come in.
进来
It is nice of you to come.
你们来了
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
剧名:我的幸福婚约
EPISODE 8 NIGHTMARES AND OMINOUS SHADOWS
第8集:噩梦与危险之影
It is nice to see you again, Prince Takaihito.
久疏拜见 尭人大人
I am happy to see you are doing well.
你们看上去很好
I am the new head of the Tatsuishi family.
小人是新继任的辰石家主
My name is Kazushi Tatsuishi.
名为辰石一志
Even though a member of my family committed a crime,
大人不计较族人犯下的重罪
you have given me permission to meet you like this.
允许小人觐见
I want to thank you from the bottom of my heart.
小人感激不尽
You do not need to worry.
不必介怀
It must have not been easy for you.
你也不容易吧
Thank you. I am humbled to hear those words.
小人不敢当
Since then, the Tatsuishi family has been
今后辰石家
under the control of the Kudo family, working at their beck and call.
会加入久堂家麾下 为重振名誉与信任
We intend to try hard to restore our good name and your trust.
鞠躬尽瘁 死而后已
On behalf of Mikado, my father, I forgive the Tatsuishi family.
我代表我父帝上 赦免辰石家
You must devote yourself to make good on your promise.
你须得牢记誓言 尽力兑现
I appreciate your clemency.
大人的宽赦 小人感激不尽
So, Prince Takaihito.
那么尭人大人
We heard that you received a revelation.
听闻您收到了天启
You must know by now that the seal of the Grave was broken.
尔等应该知道神墓大开的事吧
Yes.
是
A never-ending night will come from the underworld.
自黄泉而来的永夜即将来临
It will be a deep, everlasting darkness.
那是深邃而漫长的黑暗
Beware. A battle is forthcoming.
小心 战争即将来临
There may be those who will lose their lives.
有人或将为此丧命
So, is danger approaching
也就是说危险
this imperial city?
会降临帝都是吗?
If I foresee anything else, I shall inform you.
如果我还遇见了其他 我会通知你们的
- Yes, thank you, sir.
-多谢
Thank you for your time.
小人告退
Kiyoka.
清霞
What is it, sir?
请吩咐
I heard you got engaged.
我听说你订婚了
- Finally. - Yes.
-终于 -是
Your fiancée... well,
你的未婚妻...算了
she may experience many hardships...
今后可能会遭遇种种困难
Hardships?
困难?
You should be able to handle it.
应该没关系 你能应付
Is this a revelation too?
请问这也是天启吗?
I will bear this in mind.
在下会谨记于心
- Uh-huh. - Um, how am I doing?
-不错 -怎么样?
Let's see.
我想想
First of all, try not to hunch your shoulders.
首先要抬头挺胸
- Yes. - Keep your eyes to the front.
-是 -目视前方
- A party is a place for socializing.
-派对是供人交流的
Let's change your posture which doesn't make you look confident.
首先要抛弃那些 让你看上去毫无自信的习惯
- Yes... - Don't forget to smile.
-是 -你看你 要微笑
Yes.
是
Lift the corners of your mouth to laugh.
笑的时候嘴角上扬
Oh yes.
就是这样
You know, I once took Kiyoka to a tearoom that serves sweets.
以前我带清霞去吃甜品
Of course, we ordered some and they were delicious.
照理来说会好好享用甜品吧
Y-Yes.
是
But Kiyoka was more interested in something else rather than sweets.
但是比起甜品 清霞对别的更感兴趣
What was it?
那是什么?
The pickles that came with the sweets.
是用来搭配甜品的咸味小菜
He stared at my pickles and said,
他直勾勾地盯着小菜说
"Let me have them if you don't want them."
“如果你不要就给我吃吧”
He's surprisingly greedy about food, isn't he?
他意外地是个贪吃鬼呢
Did he, really? That is surprising.
您是说老爷吗?
Yes, that's it!
没错 就是这样
Try to smile like that naturally.
像这样自然地微笑
Yes!
是
Good response.
回答得很不错
Okay, next we'll practice walking.
接下来是走路姿势的训练
You need to walk differently in Western-style clothes.
洋装与和服的走路姿势完全不一样
Y-Yes.
明白了
ONE: ETIQUETTE FOR WESTERN ATTIRE
(一 洋装时的举止)
TWO: SMILE WHEN GREETING
(二 打招呼时微笑)
THREE: TABLE MANNERS
(三 餐桌礼仪)
Ms. Hazuki is flawless as a proper lady.
叶月小姐作为淑女无可挑剔
Taking lessons every day from somebody like her
能让她每天教导我
makes me feel that I'm able to become like her a tiny step at a time.
让我觉得自己在一点点地向她靠近
I feel like one day, I can be
我想总有一天
a proper lady deserving of being next to my husband-to-be.
我能成为配得上老爷的淑女
Prince Takaihito might know...
尭人大人
It seems as though he foresees what will happen to Miyo in the future.
或许看到了美世未来会发生什么
What is going to happen to Miyo?
她身上到底会发生什么?
Shinichi's first wife,
关于斋森真一的前妻
the birth mother of Miyo Saimori
斋森美世的亲生母亲
apparently came from the Usuba family.
应该是薄刃家的人
The Usuba family.
薄刃家族
Among the many families with supernatural abilities,
在众多异能家族中
they're said to be exceptionally unique and dangerous.
也是非常独特 被视作危险的存在
They have the ability to read minds, pry into our memories,
据说他们能够读心 潜入记忆
and even slip into dreams, they say.
甚至能深入梦境
Are Miyo's nightmares related to
美世的噩梦
the supernatural abilities of the Usuba family?
与薄刃家的异能有关吗?
But there was no break in the barrier
但是结界没有破损
nor were there any signs of external interference.
没有外界干涉的迹象
What other possibilities are left?
那么剩下的可能性是?
Get ready to be dispatched anytime.
做好随时出动的准备
Hmm? Are you going somewhere, sir?
什么?你要出门吗?
Yes. I'll be back soon.
嗯 我很快就回来
Oh, I bet you're going to see Ms. Miyo, aren't you?
你不会是要去见美世小姐吧?
It's work-related. I'll be back before it gets dark.
是工作 天黑之前我就回来
No worries here, sir.
请不用担心
What's left is how to introduce yourself,
剩下的就是自我介绍
and the rules of conversation.
和交谈时的规矩
Also, I need to teach you what to do when you are bothered by someone.
还有我得教你如何应对别人的纠缠
Thank you very much, Ms. Hazuki.
谢谢您 叶月小姐
It's for my precious little sister.
你可是我的宝贝妹妹
If I can be of any help, I'll be so happy.
我很高兴能帮上你的忙
By the way, Miyo-chan.
还有美世
Yes.
什么?
I have just one favor to ask of you.
我有一件事要拜托你
It should be okay now since we've become so close...
既然我们都这么要好了
Ms. Hazuki?
叶月小姐?
That way of addressing me.
你的称呼
When you call me,
叫我的时候
you don't have to say "Ms."
就不要加“小姐”了
I want us to be more like family.
我想和你关系更进一步
That's what we're going to be.
之后我们就是家人了
I want you to depend on me, more and more.
你可以对我撒娇 依赖我
I'm sure Kiyoka does too.
我想清霞也是一样
He may be grumpy on the surface, but he'll agree with me.
虽然他看似冷淡 但是肯定也是这么想的
Family...
家人
You don't have to be so formal.
所以你不用拘泥于规矩
I would be happy if you casually call me "Big Sister."
叫我“姐姐” 我会很高兴的
Of course, I won't force you.
当然 我不会强求你这么做
Big...
姐...
Big Sister.
姐姐大人
What's the matter?
怎么了?
Well,
那么
then is it all right if I just call you Hazuki?
我叫你“叶月姐”可以吗?
Yes, of course!
当然
Goodbye, Miyo-chan. See you tomorrow.
再见了 美世 明天见
Yes. I'll be looking forward to it.
再见 明天也请多多关照
I want to be near my husband-to-be.
我想要留在老爷身边
I want to become part of his family.
我想成为他的家人
But...
但是
what is "family"?
“家人”是什么?
It started raining so suddenly.
突然下起了雨
Weather in the summer is a pain because it changes abruptly.
夏天的天气真是多变
So, did you find any members of the Usuba family?
那么你找到薄刃家的人了吗?
I conducted a lot of research, but
我做了许多调查
records and documents concerning the Usuba family are non-existent.
但是没有有关薄刃家的记录和文献
Rumors about them seem to take on a life of their own.
只有有关他们的各类传闻
So far,
如今
the only clue we have that links to the Usuba family is Sumi Usuba.
与薄刃家有关联的只有薄刃澄美
She's the only person we know of who went by the family name of Usuba.
她是唯一自称“薄刃”的人
It's a fact that Sumi Usuba did exist.
薄刃澄美确实存在
She married Saimori and Miyo was born.
加入斋森家 生下了美世
No matter how secretive the Usuba family is,
就算薄刃家再怎么神秘
it should be impossible to erase all traces of her existence.
也不能完全消除她的痕迹
Mister?
老爷?
I want any information you can find.
什么消息都可以
Let's start with a probe into this woman named Sumi
先从曾在帝都的 名为澄美的女性这条线索
who lived in the imperial city.
开始进行调查
I need to find out
我要尽快找到
the reason for her nightmares as soon as possible.
她噩梦的原因
H-How was it?
怎么样?
It was wonderful, Miyo-chan!
美世 非常棒
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
I think you're ready to go into town and put what you learned into practice.
那么接下来就是学以致用 去城镇上逛逛
Miyo-chan, are you all right? You look tired.
美世 你没事吧?是不是累了?
I'm fine.
我没事
Are you getting enough sleep these days?
这些天睡好觉了吗?
- Yes. - Don't push yourself too hard.
-是 -不要勉强
Tell me anytime if you're not feeling well.
觉得累的时候就跟我说
Yes.
好
By the way, I heard that Kiyoka has been coming home late recently.
说起来 最近清霞回来得很晚呢
His work seems to require a lot of his time these days.
他最近工作很辛苦
Today he said he has to work overnight again.
他说今天也会在外过夜
What?
真是的
Ignoring his cute little fiancée and working all the time?
放着可爱的你不管 沉迷工作
He's disqualified as a husband.
作为丈夫是不合格的
No, no. I don't think so.
不是这样的
His working so hard makes me want to
老爷这么努力地工作
try my best while practicing with you.
让我也想要尽全力练习
Oh my, what a nice smile. That's the spirit!
你笑得真好看 就是要这样的干劲
Commander, the envoy has arrived from the Imperial Household Ministry.
队长 内廷部的使者来了
Finally.
终于来了吗?
But it's miraculous that the notoriously secretive ministry
不过那个神神秘秘的内廷部
actually decided to send us someone.
还真是痛下决心了呢
It shows the urgency of the situation.
这说明情况紧急
Let's try to get him to tell us everything about what's happening.
让我们把事情经过全部说清楚吧
How do you do?
您好
My name is Arata Tsuruki.
我叫鹤木新
SPECIAL ADVISOR ARATA TSURUKI
(内廷部 特别顾问)
I was sent here by the Imperial Household Ministry.
我受内廷省指派来此
I'm Kiyoka Kudo.
我是久堂清霞
The Commander of the Special Anti-grotesquerie Unit.
对异特殊部队的队长
Yes, I know.
久仰大名
You're even famous in social circles.
你在社交界也很有名
I heard that you push women away and are as cold as the tundra.
听说你不近女色 宛如冰原
There's no need for small talk.
寒暄就不必了
What I want to hear is about the Grave, that's all.
我想谈谈神墓的事
Ah, of course.
好的
Well then...
那么
As you know, the Grave has been exposed.
您也知道 神墓被破坏了
The Imperial Household Ministry
现在内廷部
is rushing to capture the Grotesqueries that have escaped.
希望尽快抓捕逃逸的异形
What was the aim of the perpetrators?
犯人的目的是什么?
We're still investigating, but we found
我们还在调查 不过我们在事发不远处
suspicious men collapsed near the scene.
发现了几个晕倒的可疑男子
We figured they were the perpetrators
他们大概就是真凶
but we don't know their motives.
但是我们还没查明他们的目的
What is the reason the ministry suddenly wanted to give us information?
内廷部为什么 突然愿意跟我们说明情况?
They were reluctant for a long time.
应该是非常不情愿的吧?
Currently, only about 20% of the Grotesqueries have been captured.
现在仅回收了两成异形
There are victims, too.
也出现了被害人
In other words, we are lacking manpower.
换言之 人手不足
It took a while, but the higher-ups at the ministry finally understood.
部内高层也终于明白了情况
Is anything the matter?
怎么了吗?
If you don't mind me asking,
允许我多嘴问一句
how did you end up coming here?
为什么指派你来?
You're not employed by the ministry, right?
你并不受雇于内廷部吧?
You're as good as I thought, Mr. Kudo.
不愧是久堂先生
You are correct.
你说的没错
I'm not affiliated with the Imperial Household Ministry.
我并不隶属于内廷部
But I've had an association with the ministry for a long time.
但是我常年与内廷部打交道
Usually, I run a company called Tsuruki Trading.
我平时经营着鹤木贸易公司
Since what I do daily is research and negotiation with clients,
因为我的日常工作就是 调查交易对象并与之沟通
I accept jobs like this when asked.
所以也会接受类似的工作委托
I see. So you are asked to negotiate
这样啊 所以类似 现在这样事态焦灼时
when things become entangled, such as this situation.
你会被委任交涉的工作
Yes.
没错
In the meantime, before we negotiate,
当然在交涉之前
we've found out some things about your background, too.
我也调查了你的情况
For example, I heard you got engaged recently.
比方说 我听说你最近订婚了
That's wonderful. How lucky you are.
我很羡慕你
I also would like to find a good wife
我也想觅得良人
and settle down soon.
尽快安定下来
But I'm having difficulties.
不过难以实现
Getting married is not an easy task at all.
结婚太难了
Anyway, regarding the matter at hand.
不论如何 本次事件
There was an official request, so we will participate in the operation.
既然受到正式委任 我们也会出动
Thank you very much.
多谢
I'll serve as a liaison from now on, so I'll be coming here often.
今后我将会成为中间联络人 会多有叨扰
I'll be looking forward to working with you.
就请您多多关照
Same here. Let's work hard together.
我也一样 有劳了
I wish you good luck, Mr. Kudo.
祝您武运昌隆 久堂先生
- Whoa. - Oh.
-天啊 -可怕
This is awful.
这可真是厉害
If you see Grotesqueries, report immediately.
如果发现异形 立刻报告
If you encounter them, engage with multiple forces.
如果与之交手 确保不是孤身一人
- Yes, sir.
-遵命
He was found lying down in the bushes.
据说倒在草丛里
He does have a pulse, but he's unconscious.
脉搏尚在跳动 但是昏迷不醒
Just like the men described in the report.
与报告中的男人们一样吗?
This guy is not just a victim, right?
这个人不是单纯的被害人吧?
No. In all likelihood, he's probably one of the men who opened the Grave.
十有八九 是毁坏神墓的元凶之一
That means, even if he wakes up
这意味着醒了之后
a scary interrogation would be waiting for him.
会有很可怕的审问等着他
Poor guy.
真可怜
That's a big if.
如果他能醒来的话
Not one of the men rescued in this condition has woken up so far.
这种状态被救下的人中 没有一个人苏醒
Why won't they come to?
他们昏迷不醒的原因
Nobody has figured out the mystery.
没有人知道
The curse of the Grave...
神墓的诅咒吗?
Yes. It's safe to say...
对 很有可能
they had contact with Grotesqueries that were released from the Grave.
他们与被释放的异形接触了
I see.
原来如此
Just so you know, the ability I have
先说好 我能做的
is "kaijutsu," which is dispelling curses and magic.
只是解开诅咒或者术式的“解术”
It can work on living humans,
只对活人的术式起效
but I don't know if I can dispel the curse of the dead.
死人就不知道能不能行了
There's no other way. Just try anyway.
也没有其他方法了 总之就教给你了
Got it.
明白了
How should I say... It's as if something moved in here.
怎么说呢 像是什么东西活动后的痕迹
Commander? What is it?
队长 怎么了?
It's just too quiet.
太安静了
There are no sounds.
声音消失了
Huh? What happened?
发生了什么?
This curse is...
这个诅咒
not something I can handle.
我无能为力
Is that...?
那是?
Stand back.
退下
Where...
这是哪里?
am I...?
我在哪里?
Sir!
老爷
No!
放开我
Even if you are the spirits of gifted individuals,
即使是英灵
since you've become Grotesqueries that harm humans,
既然已经变成怨灵 还袭击了人类
I must destroy you.
我不会手下留情
Sorry, but I'm going to exorcise you now!
抱歉 我会在这里消灭你们
We're almost there...
很快乐
Finally...
终于
There are already indications.
已经有预兆了
The awakening is near.
觉醒近在眼前
Yes.
是
I will protect her.
我会保护她
Because that is my role.
因为这是我的使命
So these are Grotesqueries of the Grave.
这就是神墓的异形
If they were able to enter the imperial city...
如果让这些东西入侵帝都
I will never let that happen.
我绝不会让这种事发生
Mister, give me some candy!
叔叔 给我糖果
Sure!
好的
Yes, I think you're doing very well.
嗯 我觉得你做得很好
Your posture and walking are perfect.
你的行动举止都很棒
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
Okay, let's go.
来 我们走吧
This is practice for you, but you should enjoy it too.
虽说是练习 也得让你开开心心的
Y-Yes.
是
Today's practice is in town.
今天是实习日
My husband-to-be is working hard too.
老爷也肯定在努力工作
I must work hard to get better...
我必须努力才行
to become a proper lady deserving of him as a husband.
为了成为配得上老爷的淑女
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
Miyo-chan, are you okay?
美世 你没事吧?
You look pale.
你的脸色很难看
Hmm? Oh, I'm fine.
什么?我没事
It's not good to stress yourself.
太过苛求自己可不好
Nothing good comes from worrying.
一味焦急没有好处
You are definitely showing growth.
你已经有所成长
So don't push yourself too hard.
别把自己逼得太紧
Yes.
是
I think we should go home today after all.
我们今天还是回去吧
But Hazuki, I can still...
叶月姐 我的话...
No, you can't.
不行
You must go home and take a good rest. All right?
今天回去之后要好好休息 明白吗?
I understand.
是
As I said, you need to stop stressing yourself.
我刚刚也说了 不要这么焦虑
If you get sick at the actual party, all your lessons would be in vain.
如果你在派对上病倒了 那不就前功尽弃了?
Come gather round! The picture-card show is beginning!
来吧 纸人戏就要开始了
Hey, hurry up!
快点
Wait for me!
等等我
I'm sorry.
对不起
- Are you okay? - Yes.
-你没事吧? -嗯
- Let's go! - Yes!
-我们走吧 -好
Uh...
奇怪
No, I...
我...
I can't faint...
怎么能...
in a place like this...
倒在这里...
Are you all right, Miyo?
你没事吧 美世?
Sir...
老爷
Are you all right, Ms. Miyo Saimori?
你没事吧 斋森美世小姐?